Guide to the Vassar-Yale Study Records, 1966-1967
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar-Yale Study Records
1966-1967
Vassar College
Yale University
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Records from the investigation into a proposed affiliation between Vassar College and Yale University, including relocation of Vassar to New Haven, Connecticut.
Administrative History
In 1966, Vassar College and Yale University began discussions about an alliance between the two schools. The proposal was in response to questions at both institutions about coeducation. At that time both Vassar and Yale were single sex institutions. A joint committee of administrators was formed to gather information and gauge feasibility. In the end, logistical, financial and administrative hurtles, combined with strong opposition from a large number of Vassar alumnae and faculty, put an end to the plan. But the question of coeducation remained open, and in 1969 both Vassar and Yale went coeducational.
Scope and Content Note
Records from the investigation into a proposed affiliation between Vassar College and Yale University, including possible relocation of Vassar to New Haven, Connecticut. Includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, and alumnae petitions.
Access
Unprocessed materials are restricted. The processed portion of this collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar College--Administration; Yale University
Subjects:
Coeducation
VCL Categories
Vassar College Events and Issues
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett and Elizabeth Clarke, July 2008
Acquisition Information
Vassar College transfer.
Series List
- Series I. Petitions Against Move to Yale
- Series II. Questionnaires
- Series III. Reports
- Series IV. Unprocessed Material
Container List
- Series I. Petitions Against Move to Yale
  - Class of 1900 to Class of 1907 (Folder 1.1)
  - Class of 1908 (Folder 1.2)
  - Class of 1909 to Class of 1915 (Folder 1.3)
  - Class of 1916 to Class of 1918 (Folder 1.4)
  - Class of 1919 to Class of 1921 (Folder 1.5)
  - Class of 1922 to Class of 1926 (Folder 1.6)
  - Class of 1927 to Class of 1930 (Folder 1.7)
  - Class of 1931 to Class of 1936 (Folder 2.1)
  - Class of 1937 to Class of 1942 (Folder 2.2)
  - Class of 1943 to Class of 1947 (Folder 2.3)
  - Class of 1948 to Class of 1953 (Folder 2.4)
  - Class of 1954 to Class of 1967 (Folder 2.5)
  - Multiple Classes (Folder 3.1- Folder 3.4)
- Series II. Questionnaires
  - Student Questionnaire for the Committee in New Dimensions, April 1967 (Folder 4.1)
  - General Comment Concerning Student Questionnaires (Folder 4.2)
  - Responses to Student Questionnaire, April 1967 (Folder 4.3)
  - Preliminary Results of Student Questionnaire (Folder 4.4)
  - Alumnae Questionnaire (Folder 4.5)
  - Results of Alumnae Questionnaire (Folder 4.6)
- Series III. Reports
  - Vassar-Yale Report from the Joint Study Committee, September 1967 (Box 5)
  - Vassar-Yale Study - Admissions Data (Box 5)
  - Vassar-Yale Study - Comparative Data (Box 5)
  - The New Vassar, 1964-1970: Report of the President (Box 5)
  - Vassar College: Report of the Comprehensive Planning Committee, Sep 1968 (Box 5)
  - Vassar College Departmental Reports, September 1967 (Binder 1)
  - Yale University Departmental Reports, September 1967 (Binder 2)
  - Vassar-Yale Preliminary Report from the Joint Study Committee, September 1967 (Binder 3)
- Series IV. Unprocessed Material
  - Unprocessed material (Boxes 6-14)